A Guide to the Robert Lynch Montague papers, 1882-1914
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Robert Lynch Montague papers, 1882-1914
The Library of Virginia
22001a
6.825 cu. ft. and 20 boxes
Robert Lynch Montague
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Elizabeth Hoskins Montague of Richmond, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Robert Lynch Montague was born in September 1864 in Middlesex County, Virginia, to Robert Latane Montague (1819-1880) and Cordelia Gay Eubank Montague (1835-1884). He attended the public schools in Middlesex County and Locustdale Academy in Madison County, Virginia. Montague attended the University of Virginia, where he studied law. Settling in Richmond, Virginia, Montague became a prominent attorney. He was the brother of Governor Andrew Jackson Montague (1862-1937). Montague died 24 January 1932 in Hanover County, Virginia, and is buried in Christ Episcopal Church in Middlesex County.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1882-1914, of Robert Lynch Montague (1864-1932) of Richmond, Virginia, containing his legal and political correspondence. Legal correspondence concerns cases and matters upon which he worked and political correspondence covers Virginia and national politics, specifically the political career of his brother Andrew Jackson Montague (1862-1937) Governor of Virginia and congressman. Collection contains some correspondence of Andrew Jackson Montague. Collection also includes a volume of Robert Lynch Montague's legal notes.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Andrew Jackson Montague papers, 1854-1938 (LVA accession 22001).
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1882, 1889, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, January 1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, February 1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, March-April 1892 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, May-June 1892 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, July-September 1892 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, October-December 1892 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, January-February 1893 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, March-April 1893 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, May-June 1893 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, July 1893 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, August-September 1893 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, October-November 1893 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, December 1893 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, January-February 1894 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, March-April 1894 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, May-August 1894 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, September-December 1894 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, January-March 1895 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, April-May 1895 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, June-July 1895 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, August-September 1895 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, October-December 1895 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, January-February 1896 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, March-April 1896 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, May 1896 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, June 1896 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, July 1896 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, August-September 1896 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, October-November 1896 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, December and no date 1896 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, no date [1892-1896] (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, January 1897 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, February 1897 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, March 1897 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, April-May 1897 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, June-July 1897 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, August-September 1897 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, October 1897 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, November 1897 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, December 1897 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, no date [1897-1898] (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, January-February 1898 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, March-April 1898 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, May 1898 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, June 1898 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, July-August 1898 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, September-October 1898 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, November-December 1898 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, January-April 1899 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, May-July 1899 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, August-September 1899 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, October-December 1899 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, no date [1898-1899] (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, January-February 1900 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, March-April 1900 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, May-August 1900 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, September-October 1900 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, November-December 1900 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, January 1901 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, February 1901 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, March 1901 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, April 1901 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1-15 May 1901 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 16-31 May 1901 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1-20 June 1901 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 21-30 June 1901 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, July-September 1901 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, October 1901 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, November-December 1901 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, no date [1900-1901] (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, January 1902 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, February 1902 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, March 1902 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, April 1902 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, May 1902 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, June 1902 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, July 1902 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, August 1902 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, September 1902 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, October 1902 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, November 1902 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1-15 December 1902 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 16-31 December 1902 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, no date [1902] (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1-10 January 1903 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 12-31 January 1903 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, February 1903 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 2-13 March 1903 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 16-30 March 1903 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1-10 April 1903 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 11-29 April 1903 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1-20 May 1903 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 21-30 May 1903 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 2-20 June 1903 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 21-30 June 1903 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1-10 July 1903 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 11-20 July 1903 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 21-31 July 1903 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1-10 August 1903 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 11-20 August 1903 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 21-31 August 1903 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1-15 September 1903 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 16-30 1903 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, October 1903 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, November 1903 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, December 1903 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, no date [1903] (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1-15 January 1904 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 16-30 January 1904 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, February 1904 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, March 1904 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1-15 April 1904 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 16-30 April 1904 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 2-14 May 1904 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 16-31 May 1904 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, June 1904 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, July 1904 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, August 1904 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 3-15 September 1904 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 17-30 September 1904 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, October 1904 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, November 1904 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, December 1904 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, no date [1904] (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1-14 January 1905 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 19-31 January 1905 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1-14 February 1905 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 16-28 February 1905 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1-15 March 1905 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 16-31 March 1905 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1-20 April 1905 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 21-29 April 1905 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 2-10 May 1905 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 11-17 May 1905 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 18-20 May 1905 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 21-24 May 1905 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 25-31 May 1905 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1-10 June 1905 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 12-20 June 1905 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 21-27 June 1905 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 28-30 June 1905 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1-4 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 5-7 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 8-11 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 12-14 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 15-18 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 19-20 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 21-23 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 24-25 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 26-27 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 28 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 29-30 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Correspondence (incoming), 31 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Correspondence (outgoing), 31 July 1905 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1 August 1905 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 2 August 1905 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 3-4 August 1905 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 5 August 1905 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 6-8 August 1905 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 9-11 August 1905 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 12-14 August 1905 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 15-18 August 1905 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 19-31 August 1905 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, September 1905 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1-14 October 1905 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 16-31 October 1905 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1-15 November 1905 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 16-28 November 1905 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, December 1905 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, no date [1905] (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, January-March, May-August 1906 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, September 1906 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, October 1906 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, November 1906 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, December 1906 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, no date [1906-1907] (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1-14 January 1907 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 16-31 January 1907 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, February 1907 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1-12 March 1907 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 13-30 March 1907 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, April 1907 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, May 1907 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, June 1907 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1-19 July 1907 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 20-31 July 1907 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 2-15 August 1907 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 16-31 August 1907 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1-20 September 1907 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 21-30 September 1907 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 2-10 October 1907 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 11-19 October 1907 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 21-31 October 1907 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1-10 November 1907 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 11-20 November 1907 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 21-30 November 1907 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 2-14 December 1907 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 16-31 December 1907 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 2-18 January 1908 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 21-30 January 1908 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 3-12 February 1908 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 13-29 February 1908 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 2-14 March 1908 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 17-31 March 1908 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1-20 April 1908 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 21-30 April 1908 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1-15 May 1908 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 16-30 May 1908 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1-20 June 1908 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 22-30 June 1908 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1-24 July 1908 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 25-31 July 1908 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, August 1908 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, September 1908 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, October 1908 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, November 1908 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1-19 December 1908 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 21-31 December 1908 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, no date [1908] (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1-12 January 1909 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 13-19 January 1909 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 21-31 January 1909 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1-12 February 1909 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 13-27 February 1909 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1-15 March 1909 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 16-31 March 1909 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1-14 April 1909 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 16-30 April 1909 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, May 1909 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1-15 June 1909 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 16-30 June 1909 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1-15 July 1909 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 16-31 July 1909 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, August-December 1909 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, no date [1909] (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, January-April 1910 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 2-12 May 1910 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 13-24 May 1910 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 25-31 May 1910 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1-10 June 1910 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 11-20 June 1910 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 21-30 June 1910 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1-9 July 1910 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 11-19 July 1910 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 22-30 July 1910 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1-10 August 1910 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 11-19 August 1910 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 22-31 August 1910 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1-15 September 1910 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 16-30 September 1910 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1-15 October 1910 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 17-31 October 1910 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, November 1910 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, no date [1910] (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, January 1912 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1-10 February 1912 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 11-29 February 1912 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, March 1912 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1-8 April 1912 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 9-17 April 1912 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 18-30 April 1912 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1-15 May 1912 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 16-31 May 1912 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, June 1912 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1-12 July 1912 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 13-31 July 1912 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1-24 August 1912 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 26-31 August 1912 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, September 1912 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1-10 October 1912 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 11-20 October 1912 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 21-31 October 1912 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1-15 November 1912 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 16-30 November 1912 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, December 1912 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, no date [1912] (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1-10 January 1913 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 13-31 January 1913 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1-7 February 1913 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 8-20 February 1913 (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 21-28 February 1913 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1-11 March 1913 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 12-24 March 1913 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 25-31 March 1913 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1-9 April 1913 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 10-18 April 1913 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 19-23 April 1913 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 24-30 April 1913 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1-10 May 1913 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 11-20 May 1913 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 21-31 May 1913 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 2-10 June 1913 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 11-18 June 1913 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 19-30 June 1913 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1-10 July 1913 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 11-20 July 1913 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 21-31 July 1913 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1-15 August 1913 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 18-30 August 1913 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 2-20 September 1913 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 22-30 September 1913 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1-8 October 1913 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 9-23 October 1913 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 24-31 October 1913 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, November 1913 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, December 1913 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, no date [1913] (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1-20 January 1914 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 21-31 January 1914 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1-5 February 1914 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 6-14 February 1914 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 16-20 February 1914 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 21-28 February 1914 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1-10 March 1914 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 11-20 March 1914 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 21-31 March 1914 (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 2-10 April 1914 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 11-30 April 1914 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1-20 May 1914 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 21-30 May 1914 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1-10 June 1914 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 11-20 June 1914 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 22-30 June 1914 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1-10 July 1914 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 11-20 July 1914 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 21-31 July 1914 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, August 1914 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1-15 September 1914 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 16-30 September 1914 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1-15 October 1914 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 16-31 October 1914 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, November 1914 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, no date [1914] (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Legal notes (Box 20, Folder 1)